Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller Papers, ca. 1870-1940
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Books Reviewed by Schiller
  - Schiller, Ferdinand Canning Scott. Reviews of various books by various authors. v.p. v.d., 199 items. Holograph, typescript, galleys, and clippings. (Box 10)
    - James, William. The varieties of religious experience, a study in human nature. (Box 10)
    - Jerusalem, W. Einleitung in die Philosophie. (Box 10)
    - Jespersen. Otto. The philosophy of grammar. (Box 10)
    - Joachim, Harold H. The nature of truth. (Box 10)
    - Joad, C.E.M. Modern philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Johnson, W.E. Logic. Part 1. (Box 10)
    - Johnson, W.E. Logic. Part 2. Demonstrative inference, deductive and inductive. (Box 10)
    - Johnson, W.E. Logic. Part 3. The logical foundations of science. (Box 10)
    - Johnston, G.A. The development of Berkeley's philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Joseph, H.W.B. Some problems in ethics. (Box 10)
    - Kagey, Rudolf. The growth of F.H. Bradley's logic. (Box 10)
    - Kallen, Horace M., ed. American philosophy today and tomorrow. (Box 10)
    - Kamiat, Arnold H. The critique of poor reason. (Box 10)
    - Keller, Albert Galloway. Societal evolution: a study of the evolutionary basis of the science of society. (Box 10)
      See Machen, Arthur.
    - King, William P., ed. Behaviorism, a battle line. (Box 10)
    - Knox, Howard V. The evolution of truth and other essays. (Box 10)
    - Knox, Howard V. The will to be free. (Box 10)
    - König, Edmund. Ueber die letzten Fragen der Erkenntnis-theorie und dem Gegensatz des transendentalen Idealismus und Realismus. (Box 10)
    - Laird, John. Knowledge, belief and opinion. (Box 10)
    - Lambek, C. Essay on the foundation of cognition. (Box 10)
    - Lambert, Henry. The nature of history. (Box 10)
    - Lawton, George. The drama of life after death, a study of the spiritualist religion. (Box 10)
    - Lehman. Alf. Aberglauben und Zauberei. (Box 10)
    - Lichtenberger, Henri. The gospel of superman: the philosophy of Friedrick Nietzsche. (Box 10)
    - Liebert Arthur. Die Krise des Idealismus. (Box 10)
    - Lightfall, E.D. The person of evolution, studies of instinct as contributions to a philosophy of evolution. (Box 10)
    - Locke, John. An essay concerning human understanding. Edited by A.S. Pringle-Pattison. (Box 10)
    - Lodge, Sir Oliver. Modern problems. (Box 10)
    - Lovejoy, Arthur O. The great chain of being, a study of the history of an idea. The William James Lectures delivered at Harvard University. 1933. (Box 10)
    - Lünemann, Arthur. Logik der Philosophie, Gründzüge einer Umgestaltung der Formalen Logik. (Box 10)
    - Mc Dougall, William. The frontiers of psychology. (Box 10)
    - Mc Dougall, William. Is America safe for democracy? 6 lectures given at the Lowell Institute of Boston. (Box 10)
    - Mace, C.A. The principles of logic, an introductory survey. (Box 10)
    - Machen, Arthur. The Bowmen and other legends of the War. (Box 10)
    - Macintosh, D.C., ed. Religious realism. (Box 10)
    - McTaggart, J.M.T. Ellis. Philosophical studies. (Box 10)
    - McTaggart, J.M.T. Ellis. Studies in the hegelian dialectic. (Box 10)
    - Marett, J.R. de la H. Race, sex and environment, a study of mineral deficiency in human evolution. (Box 10)
    - Marett, R.R. Faith, hope, and charity in primitive religion. (Box 10)
    - Marett, R.R. Sacraments of simple folk. (Box 10)
    - Marvin, F.S. Progress and history. (Box 10)
    - Mead, George H. Mind, self and society, from the standpoint of a social behaviorist. (Box 10)
    - Mead, George H. Movements of thought in the nineteenth century. (Box 10)
    - Mead, George Herbert. The philosophy of the present. (Box 10)
    - Mercier, Louis J.A. The challenge of humanism, an essay in comparative criticism. (Box 10)
    - Metz, Rudolf. Die philosophischen Stroemungen der Gegenwart in Grossbrittanien. vol.1. (Box 10)
    - Montague, William Pepperell. Belief unbound, a promethian religion for the modern world. (Box 10)
    - Morris, Charles W. Six theories of mind. (Box 10)
    - Morrow, Glen R. Studies in the Platonic epistles, with a translation and notes. (Box 10)
    - Müller-Freienfels, Richard. Irrationalismus, um_____ einer Erkenninis __________. (Box 10)
    - Münsterberg. Psychology and mysticism. (Box 10)
    - Nevius, John L. Demon possession and allied themes, being an inductive study of phenomena of our own times. (Box 10)
    - Nietzsche, Friedrich. The complete works. (Box 10)
    - Nietzsche, Friedrich. Thus spake Zarathrustra, a book for all and none. (Box 10)
    - Northridge, W.L. Modern theories of the unconscious. (Box 10)
      See Edgell, Beatrice.
    - Orr, John. English deism, its roots and its fruits. (Box 10)
    - Oakeley, Hilda D. History and the self, a study in the roots of history and the relations of history and ethics. (Box 10)
      See Baker, Rannie Belle.
    - Pacotte, Julian. La logique et l'empirisme radical. (Box 10)
      See Carnap.
    - Pearson, Norman. The soul and its story. (Box 10)
    - Peirce, Charles S. Chance love and logic: philosophical essays. (Box 10)
    - Peirce, Charles Sanders. Collected Papers. Edited by Charles Hartshorne and Paul Weiss
      - vol.1. (Box 10)
      - vol.2: Elements of logic. (Box 10)
      - vol.3: Exact logic. (Box 10)
      - vol.5: Pragmatism and pragmaticism. (Box 10)
      - vol.6: Scientific metaphysics. (Box 10)
    - Penny, A.J. Studies in Jacob Böhme. (Box 10)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton. Present philosophical tendencies: a critical survey of naturalism, idealism, pragmatism and realism, together with a synopsis of the philosophy of William James. (Box 10)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton. The thought and character of William James, as revealed in umpublished correspondence and notes, together with his published writings. vol.1. (Box 10)
    - Pekron, Houston. Huxley, prophet of science. (Box 10)
    - Philosophic essays for Alfred North Whitehead. (Box 10)
    - Pratt, James Bissett. Adventures in philosophy and religion. (Box 10)
    - Price, H.H. Truth and corrigibility, an inaugural lecture delivered before the University of Oxford. (Box 10)
    - Prince, Morton. The unconscious, the fundamentals of human personality normal and abnormal. (Box 10)
    - Prince, Walter Franklin. Proceedings of the American Society for Psychical Research. The Doris Fischer case of multiple personality. (Box 10)
    - Pringle-Pattison, A. Seth. The idea of immortality. Gifford lectures delivered in the University of Edinburgh in the year 1922. (Box 10)
    - Problems of personality, studies presented to Dr. Morton Prince, pioneer in American psychopathology. (Box 10)
    - Reiser, Oliver L. Humanistic logic for the mind in action. (Box 10)
    - Richards, Philip S. Belief in man. (Box 10)
    - Robertson, G. Croom. Elements of psychology. (Box 10)
    - Robinson, James Harvey. The mind in the making. (Box 10)
    - Rogers, Arthur Kenyon. The Socratic problem. (Box 10)
    - Romanes, George John. Darwin and after Darwin. An exposition of the Darwinian theory and a discussion of post-Darwinian questions. (Box 10)
    - Romanes, George John. An examination of Weismannism. (Box 10)
    - Ross, W.D. Aristotle. (Box 10)
    - Rossi, M.M. Bishop Berkeley. (Box 10)
      See Hone, J.M.
    - Russell, Bertrand. The conquest of happiness. (Box 10)
    - Russell, Bertrand. Education and the social order. (Box 10)
    - Russell, Bertrand. Religion and science. (Box 10)
    - Russell, Bertrand. The scientific outlook. (Box 10)
    - Salomaa, J.E. Idealismus und realismus in der englischen Philosophie der Gegenwart. (Box 10)
    - Salomaa, J.E. Das Problem der Wahrheit. (Box 10)
    - Salzi, Pierre. La sensation, étude de la genese et de son role dans la connaissance. (Box 10)
    - Samson, Leon. The new humanism. (Box 10)
    - Santayana, George. The life of reason, or the phases of human progress. vol.3: Reason in religion. vol.4: Reason in art. vol.5: Reason in science. (Box 10)
    - Santayana, George. Obiter scripta, lectures, essays, and reviews. (Box 10)
    - Santayana, George. Some turns of thought in modern philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Santayana, George. The unknowable. The Herbert Spencer lecture delivered at Oxford. (Box 10)
    - Saurat, Denis. Literature and the occult tradition. (Box 10)
    - Schelling. Of human freedom. (Box 10)
    - Schinz, Albert. Anti-pragmatisme, examen des droits respectifs de l'aristocratie intellectuell et de la démocratiesociale. (Box 10)
    - Schlick, Moritz. Sur le fondement de la connaissance. (Box 10)
    - Schulz, Julius. Das Ich und die Physik. (Box 10)
    - Schweitzer, Albert. The decay and the restoration of civilisation: the philosophy of civilisation. Part 1. (Box 10)
    - Schweitzer, Albert. Civilisation and ethics. Part 2. The philosophy of civilisation. (Box 10)
    - Segerstedt, Torgny T. Value and reality in Bradley's philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Sheen, Fulton J. God and intelligence in modern philosophy. A critical study in the light of the philosophy of St. Thomas. (Box 10)
    - Sidis, Boris. Multiple personality, an experimental investigation into the nature of human individuality. (Box 10)
    - Smith, S.G. Social pathology. (Box 10)
    - Smith, Thomas Vernon, ed. Essays in philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Smith, Thomas Vernon. The philosophic way of life. (Box 10)
    - Spencer, Frederick A.M. The future life, a new interpretation of the Christian doctrine. (Box 10)
    - Spencer, Herbert. An autobiography. (Box 10)
    - Spicer, E.E. Aristotle's conception of the soul. (Box 10)
    - Stein, Ludwig. Philosophical currents of the present day. (Box 10)
    - Sturt, Henry. Human value, an ethical essay. (Box 10)
    - Sullivan, J.W.N. Science, a new outlook. (Box 10)
    - Swift, Edgar James. The jungle of the mind. (Box 10)
    - Taylor, A.E. Plato, the man and his work. (Box 10)
    - Taylor, A.E. [title undecipherable]. (Box 10)
    - Tennant, F.R. Philosophy of the sciences, or the relation between the departments of knowledge. (Box 10)
    - Thomson, Sir S. Arthur. Riddles of science. (Box 10)
    - Troiano, P.R. Le base dell' umanismo. (Box 10)
    - Turner, J.E. An examination of William James' philosophy. A critical essay for the general reader. (Box 10)
    - Ushenka, F.P. The theory of logic, an introductory text. (Box 10)
  - Reviews (Concluded)
    - Vaihinger, H. Die Philosophie des als ob. System der theoretischen, praktischen und religiösen Fiktionen der Menschheit auf Grund eines idealistischen Positivismus, mit einem Anhang über Kant und Nietzsche. (Box 10)
    - Wahl, Jean. The pluralist philosophies of England and America. Reviewed with Dewey, John, Nature and experience. (Box 10)
    - Warbeke, John M. The searching mind of Greece. (Box 10)
    - Ward. A study of Kant. (Box 10)
    - Warren, Howard C. A history of the association psychology. Reviewed with Woodworth, Robert S., Psychology. (Box 10)
    - Wells, H.G. Modern utopia. (Box 10)
    - Whetham, William Cecil Dampier, and Whetham, Catherine Durning. Science and the human mind: a critical and historical account of the development of natural knowledge. (Box 10)
    - Wild, John. George Berkeley, a study of his life and philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Windelband, Wilhelm. Platon. (Box 10)
    - Wolfenden, J.F. The approach to philosophy. (Box 10)
    - Woods, Frederick Adams. The influence of monarchs: steps in a new science of history. (Box 10)
    - Woodworth, Robert S. Psychology, a study of mental life. (Box 10)
    - Zaragüeta Benguechea, Juan. Contribucion del lenguaje a la filosofia de los valores. (Box 10)
- Holograph Notebooks
  - Notebook no.1, n.p. n.d.
    - Bradley's logic. (Box 11)
    - Notes on Notes of Cauman's Aristotelian. Logic Lecture. (Box 11)
    - Pluralism and Monism. (Box 11)
    - Reality and idealism. (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes and inserts. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.2, n.p. 1884
    - Plato Republic. (Box 11)
    - Allegory of cave. (Box 11)
    - Logical development of evil. (Box 11)
    - Tyrannical man. (Box 11)
    - The myth of the future life. (Box 11)
    - [Story, visit to Athena]. (Box 11)
    - Speech made before the Brakenbury Debating Society. February 1884. (Box 11)
    - Philosophic questions: Aristotle, modern metaphysics, ethics, modern logic, modern political philosophy, psychology. (Box 11)
    - Hobbes' 'Computation.' (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.3, n.p. 1886
    - Mr. Alexander's moral philosophy. January 1886. (Box 11)
    - Mr. Nettleship's theory of knowledge. January 1886. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.4, n.p. 1886-87
    - Aristotelian logic: extracts from Bradley's notes on Mr. Nettleship's lectures. (Box 11)
    - Arnold essay. 1886. Causes of Decline of Roman Republic. (Box 11)
    - Chapter outline of The riddles of the sphinx. (Box 11)
    - Aphorisms November 1986. 1. Evolutionist theories. (Box 11)
    - Free will. November 1987. (Box 11)
    - Notes on Berkeley. (Box 11)
    - Essays 1886:
      - The nature and province of logic. (Box 11)
      - The presuppositions of induction and the conception of cause. (Box 11)
      - On inconceivability as the test of truth. (Box 11)
      - The nature of arithmetical judgments. (Box 11)
      - Note on the relation of Kant's theory to 'experience' theories. (Box 11)
      - On the question of the theory of causation. (Box 11)
      - The nature of geometrical judgments. (Box 11)
      - The ambiguities of the word law. (Box 11)
      - Relation of legality to morality. (Box 11)
      - Free will and freedom and the ambiguity of the word. (Box 11)
      - Conscience is an imitation within us of the government without us. (Box 11)
      - Analyse our idea of justice, compare the conceptions of it in Plato and Aristotle. (Box 11)
      - On what principle would you determine the justificability of resistance to a de facto sovereign? Is the true objective of the state sufficiently described as consisting in the realization of individual liberty? (Box 11)
      - The proper distribution of political rights is a question of expedience not of justice. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.5, n.p. 1885
    - Plato's attitude towards contemporary politics. (Box 11)
    - Aristotle's criticism of the Platonic communism. (Box 11)
    - Aristotle's criticism of Sparta. (Box 11)
    - Comparison of Aristotle's list of the virtues with Plato's and its defects. (Box 11)
    - Essays for the Master 1885. (Box 11)
    - The doctrine of utility regarded as the basis of ethics. (Box 11)
    - The origin, nature, and basis of our moral ideas. (Box 11)
    - Consciousness and habit, their relation to _____ and to the freedom of the will. (Box 11)
    - Are morals to be regarded as certain or uncertain and in what does their certainty or uncertainty consist? (Box 11)
    - The meaning of the word science, the use and abuse of the term. (Box 11)
    - The relation of art to morality. (Box 11)
    - The nature of the relation of subject and object, cause and effect, ends and means--at what point in the history of philosophy do they appear? (Box 11)
    - Exercises in Greek and Latin. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.6, Oxford. 1887-88
    - Philosophic essays. Holograph copies of papers read before the Oxford Philosophic Society. (Box 11)
    - 1. On H. Spencer's Data of ethics 1887. (Box 11)
    - 2. Essay on infinity 1888. (Box 11)
    - 3. Essay on the population question. 1887. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.7, n.p. n.d.
    - Appendix 2: Ethical corollaries. Pages numbered 539-574. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.8, n.p. n.d.
    - Mr. Nettleship's moral philosophy. (Box 11)
    - Bacon's Novum organum. (Box 11)
    - Aristotle's metaphysics. (Box 11)
    - Theories of Sp_____. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.9, n.p. n.d.
    - Notes on Berkeley. 1685-1753. (Box 11)
    - Manuscript about Kant by F.C. Borenschen(?). (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.10, n.p. n.d.
    - Polybius [school notes]. (Box 11)
    - H. Spencer's Data of ethics. (Box 11)
    - Plutarch. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.11, n.p. 1883-1899
    - Diary. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.12, n.p. 1882-1896
    - Budget. 1882-1896. (Box 11)
    - Record of a seance. June 20, 1884. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.13, n.p. 1886
    - Record of expenditures. 1886. (Box 11)
    - Financial notes, record of purchases of stock, etc. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.14, n.p. n.d.
    - Address book. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.15, n.p. n.d.
    - Alphabetical list of names. (Box 11)
  - Notebook no.16, n.p. n.d.
    - Lists of articles, reviews, etc. dated.
  - Notebook no.17 and Notebook #18, n.p. n.d.
    - Miscellaneous notes. (Box 11)
- Material Pertaining to the Posthumous Publication of Our Human Truths
  - Our human truths, Los Angeles. ca. 1937., 248 leaves. Typescript with corrections by Louise Schiller and publisher. (Box 12)
  - Truth with a smile [later titled Our human truths], New York, Columbia University Press. 1938., 111 sheets. Galleys with corrections by Louise Schiller. 2 copies of sheet 53. (Box 12)
  - Our human truths, New York, Columbia University Press. 1938., 114 sheets. Galleys. Incomplete. With underlining in red. (Box 12)
  - Index of Our human truths, New York, Columbia University Press. 1938., 9 sheets. Galley. (Box 12)
    Also: 7 additional sheets. Compiled by Louise Schiller.
  - Notes relating to the publication of Our human truths. n.p. n.d., 2 leaves. Louise Schiller's holograph. (Box 12)
    Also: 1 leaf, typescript, note for Mrs. Schiller.
  - Correspondence Regarding the Publication of Our Human Truths. v.p. v.d.
    - Columbia University. Press. (Box 12)
      - 22 letters to LSS., 3 enclosures. (Box 12)
    - Current History and Forum. New York. (Box 12)
      - 1 letter to LSS. (Box 12)
    - Flewelling, Ralph Tyler, 1871-1960
      - 1 letter to LSS. (Box 12)
    - The nineteenth century and after [periodical]. (Box 12)
      See The twentieth century [periodical].
    - The Twentieth Century [Periodical]. London (Box 12)
      - 1 letter to LSS. (Box 12)
    - University of Southern California
      - 1 letter to LSS. (Box 12)
- Manuscripts and Galleys by Persons Other Than FCS Schiller
  - Dewey, John. A trenchant attack on logic. (review of Formal Logic). n.p. 1912, Lit leader., 2 sheets. Galley with corrections. (Box 12, Box 7)
  - Dewey, John. [memorial address on Schiller], n.p. November 1937., 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 12)
  - Knox, Howard Vicenté. Methods of inductive enquiry, Bocken. 1893., 26 leaves. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Moore, Ernest C. [untitled article on FCS Schiller], Los Angeles. ca. 1937., 4 leaves. Typescript, signed. (Box 12)
    Also: 4 leaves, carbon copy, and 2 leaves, carbon copy of typescript, extracts from above revised to form obituary of FCS Schiller.
  - Who's who in Oxfordshire. Schiller, Ferdinand Canning Scott, London. ca. 1936., 2 leaves. Printer's proof with corrections by FCS Schiller. (Box 12)
  - Willett, Mrs. Extracts from Mrs. Willett's Scripts. n.p. 1913., 1 sheet. Galley with copious notes by FCS Schiller. (Box 12)
  - Dr. FCS Schiller deceased, author unknown, n.p. ca. 1938., 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 12)
    Appears to be attorney's statement regarding FCS Schiller' nationality and legal residence.
  - Extracts from the College Minute Book, author unknown, Oxford. 1927., 1 leaf. Manuscript. (Box 12)
    re the election of FCS Schiller to an Extraordinary Fellowship.
  - Manuscript in old German script, author unknown, n. p. n.d., 1 leaf. Manuscript. (Box 12)
- Articles, Pamphlets, Lectures, and Symposia
  - Absolutism in extremis? Mind, vol.19, N.S., no.76., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The ambiguity of truth. Mind, vol.15, N.S., no.58., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The answers to the American branch's questionnaire regarding human sentiment as to a future life. Proceedings of the Society for Psychical Research. n.d., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Are all judgments 'practical'? Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods, vol.12 no.25. December 9, 1915., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Aristotle and the practical syllogism. Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods, vol.14 no.24. November 22, 1917., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Aristotle's refutation of 'Aristotelian' logic. Mind, vol.23, N.S., no.89., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - The British dilemma. The Saturday Review of Literature, vol.5 no.42. May 11, 1929., 1 copy [in separate folder]. (Box 13)
  - The case for eugenics. The Dalhouse Review. n.d., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Cassandra's apologia. Mind, vol.27, N.S., no.105., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Choice. The Hibbert Journal. n.d., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Creation, emergence, novelty. Meeting of the Aristotelian Society. November 24, 1930., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The definition of 'pragmatism' and 'humanism'. Mind, vol.14, N.S., no.54., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Do men desire immortality? Fortnightly Review. September 1901., 1 copy with holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Dr. Mercier and formal logic. Mind, vol.23, N.S., no.92., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Empiricism and the absolute. Mind, vol.14, N.S., no.55., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Error. Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society. 1911., 4 copies. Congresso Internazionale di Filosofia, April 1911, 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - The ethical basis of metaphysics. International Journal of Ethics. July, 1903., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Eugenics as a moral ideal. The Eugenics Review, vol.22 no.2., 1 copy. (Box 13)
    Also: Arhiva Pentru Stiinta, n.d., 1 copy.
  - Die Eugenik als sittliches Ideal. Archiv für Rassen- und Gesellschaftsbiologie, Bd. 14. 1930., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Eugenics versus civilization. The Eugenics Review. July 1921., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Fact and value. The Proceedings of the Sixth International Congress of Philosophy. n.d. (Box 13)
  - Faith, reason, and religion. The Hibbert Journal. n.d., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Formalism again. Mind, vol.41, N.S., no.164., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Formalism and the a fortiori. Mind, vol.27, N.S., no.106., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - How 'propositions' mean. The Journal of Philosophy, vol.27 no.23. November 6, 1930. (Box 13)
  - Human sentiment as to a future life. (Box 13)
    See The answers to the American branch's questionnaire regarding human sentiment as to a future life.
  - Humanism, intuitionism and objective reality. Mind, vol.18, N.S., no.72., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - The humanism of Protagoras. Mind, vol.20, N.S., no.78., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - An idealist in extremis. Mind, vol.31, N.S., no.122., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - In defence of humanism. Mind, vol.13, N.S., no.52., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - The indetermination of meanings. Mind, vol.24, N.S., no.96., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - The infinite regress of proof. Mind, vol.37, N.S., no.147., 1 copy with holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - The infinite whole. Mind, vol.33, N.S., no.130., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - Instrumentalism and idealism. Mind, vol.34, N.S., no.133., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - Is Mr. Bradley becoming a pragmatist? Mind, vol.17, N.S., no.67., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Judgments versus propositions. Mind, vol.35 no.139., 3 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)
  - Logic and formalism. Mind, vol.28, N.S., no.110., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Logic or psychology? Mind, vol.18, N.S., no.71., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Lotze's monism. The Philosophical Review, vol.5 no.3. May 1896., 2 copies. (Box 13)
  - Mr. Bradley's theory of truth. Mind, vol.16, N.S., no.63., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - Mr. Russell's psychology. The Journal of Philosophy, vol.19 no.11. May 25, 1922., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - National self-selection. The Eugenics Review. April 1910., 1 copy. (Box 13)
  - The new developments of Mr. Bradley's philosophy. Mind, vol.24, N.S., no.95., 3 copies. (Box 13)
  - Novelty. Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society. October 10, 1921., 2 copies. one of which has holograph corrections. (Box 13)